<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adson Costanzi Filho</title>
    <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adson Costanzi Filho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions for R Users</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/04/01/github-actions-for-r-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/04/01/github-actions-for-r-users/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Recently I was introduced by some friends to the GitHub Actions and how it could help me execute tasks like: deploy my Shiny Apps, deploy this Blogdown, perform automated tests in packages, refresh data, and more. So, I decided to give it a try, and it was so simple and saved me so many work hours that I decided to write this post explaining how R developers can make good use of this amazing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSGo Package</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/25/csgo-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/25/csgo-package/</guid>
      <description>Overview  
The CSGo package is an R client for accessing Steam’s REST API specifically for the Counter-Strike Global Offensive Game (CS Go) data. Check out the Steam documentation website and the Package Page for more information.
 Installation To get the current released version from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;CSGo&amp;quot;) To get the current development version from GitHub:
# install.packages(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;) devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;adsoncostanzifilho/CSGo&amp;quot;)  Example The first step to use the CSGo package is to have your own credentials (API key) to pull the CSGo data from the Steam API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Development Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/17/package-development-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/17/package-development-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Motivation  If you are using a script more than 3 times it is time to create a function and if you are using a function in 3 different projects it is time to create a package. “I heard it from someone, but I don’t remember who..”
 Recently I experienced the whole flow to create a new R package with the help of amazing packages like devtools, usethis, pkgdown, and roxygen2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/25/blogdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/25/blogdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I had the idea of writing some “walking through” about blogdown, first because it was my first time using the package and I still have all the necessary steps fresh in my mind and second because probably I will need to have it all documented if I decided to refresh this blog one day. Of course, there are a lot of great tutorials about blogdown over the internet (the blogdown book for example), but maybe someone could find this one easier in some way…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining Tool</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/24/text-mining-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/24/text-mining-tool/</guid>
      <description>Overview  
Text Mining Tool is an interface developed in R using mainly the shiny, tidytext and rtweet packages. The idea of this interface is to allow to you make your own text analysis using live Twitter data.
The tool is online on shinyapps’ repository at the address https://adsoncostanzi.shinyapps.io/TextMining/.
 How does this interface work? The interface is divided into 5 tabs presented in the menu on the left: Home , Search , Word Cloud , Sentiment Analysis and, Topic Modeling .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>soothsayeR</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/23/soothsayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/23/soothsayer/</guid>
      <description>Overview  
SoothsayeR is an interface based on the old prank called ‘Peter answers’..
The game’s idea is to play with your friends making questions that you know the answer, and make them believe that R is who is answering…
The app demonstrates how easy it is to integrate Shiny with Javascript through the shinyjs library.
The tool is online on shinyapps’ repository at the address https://adsoncostanzi.shinyapps.io/soothsayeR/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Adson Costanzi Filho Senior Data Scientist at Evalueserve I am a statistician majored at UFRGS and currently I am working as a Data Scientist at Evalueserve, Chile.I really love everything related to the data world, indeed I spend a good part of my free time reading the news about it. I am also lucky to have near me a lot of other crazy guys who enjoy discussing with me about data science, statistics, and R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
