<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Adson Costanzi Filho</title>
    <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/categories/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Adson Costanzi Filho</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why not both?</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/07/13/why-not-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/07/13/why-not-both/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I believe the most common discussion on data science teams is R vs Python. I saw myself in some of these discussions a couple of times and my position is always “Why not use both?”. The idea of this post is not to compare R vs Python but to show how easy it is to integrate both languages using APIs (LIKE A PRO), this way we can use the best of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions for R Users</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/04/01/github-actions-for-r-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/04/01/github-actions-for-r-users/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Recently I was introduced by some friends to the GitHub Actions and how it could help me execute tasks like: deploy my Shiny Apps, deploy this Blogdown, perform automated tests in packages, refresh data, and more. So, I decided to give it a try, and it was so simple and saved me so many work hours that I decided to write this post explaining how R developers can make good use of this amazing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Package Development Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/17/package-development-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2021/03/17/package-development-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Motivation  If you are using a script more than 3 times it is time to create a function and if you are using a function in 3 different projects it is time to create a package. “I heard it from someone, but I don’t remember who..”
 Recently I experienced the whole flow to create a new R package with the help of amazing packages like devtools, usethis, pkgdown, and roxygen2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/25/blogdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adsoncostanzifilho.github.io/blog/2020/11/25/blogdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I had the idea of writing some “walking through” about blogdown, first because it was my first time using the package and I still have all the necessary steps fresh in my mind and second because probably I will need to have it all documented if I decided to refresh this blog one day. Of course, there are a lot of great tutorials about blogdown over the internet (the blogdown book for example), but maybe someone could find this one easier in some way…</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
